<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<section xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:id="_namespace_simple_pie" xml:lang="fr">
<title>Référence de l&apos;espace de nommage SimplePie</title>
<indexterm><primary>SimplePie</primary></indexterm>
<section>
<title>Description détaillée</title>

<para><link linkend="_class_simple_pie">SimplePie</link></para>

<para>A PHP-Based RSS and Atom Feed Framework. Takes the hard work out of managing a complete RSS/Atom solution.</para>

<para>Copyright (c) 2004-2016, Ryan Parman, Sam Sneddon, Ryan McCue, and contributors All rights reserved.</para>

<para>Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met: <literallayout><computeroutput>* Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, this list of
  conditions and the following disclaimer.

* Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice, this list
  of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation and/or other materials
  provided with the distribution.

* Neither the name of the SimplePie Team nor the names of its contributors may be used
  to endorse or promote products derived from this software without specific prior
  written permission.
</computeroutput></literallayout> THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS &quot;AS IS&quot; AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.</para>

<para><formalpara><title>Copyright</title>

<para>2004-2016 Ryan Parman, Sam Sneddon, Ryan McCue </para>
</formalpara>
<formalpara><title>Auteur</title>

<para>Ryan Parman </para>

<para>Sam Sneddon </para>

<para>Ryan McCue <link linkend="_">SimplePie  <link xlink:href="http://www.opensource.org/licenses/bsd-license.php">http://www.opensource.org/licenses/bsd-license.php</link> BSD License Autoloader class  API SimplePie A PHP-Based RSS and Atom Feed Framework. Takes the hard work out of managing a complete RSS/Atom solution. Copyright (c) 2004-2017, Ryan Parman, Sam Sneddon, Ryan McCue, and contributors All rights reserved. Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are met: Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer. Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer in the documentation and/or other materials provided with the distribution. Neither the name of the SimplePie Team nor the names of its contributors may be used to endorse or promote products derived from this software without specific prior written permission.  THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS &quot;AS IS&quot; AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND CONTRIBUTORS BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.  1.5.8  2004-2017 Ryan Parman, Sam Sneddon, Ryan McCue  Ryan Parman  Sam Sneddon  Ryan McCue  <link xlink:href="http://simplepie.org/">http://simplepie.org/</link> SimplePie  <link xlink:href="http://www.opensource.org/licenses/bsd-license.php">http://www.opensource.org/licenses/bsd-license.php</link> BSD License SimplePie  API Manages all author-related data Used by { SimplePie_Item::get_author()} and { SimplePie::get_authors()} This class can be overloaded with { SimplePie::set_author_class()}  API Used to create cache objects This class can be overloaded with { SimplePie::set_cache_class()}, although the preferred way is to create your own handler via { register()}  Caching Base for cache objects Classes to be used with { SimplePie_Cache::register()} are expected to implement this interface.  Caching Base class for database-based caches  Caching Caches data to the filesystem  Caching Caches data to memcache Registered for URLs with the &quot;memcache&quot; protocol For example, <computeroutput>memcache://localhost:11211/?timeout=3600&amp;prefix=sp_</computeroutput> will connect to memcache on <computeroutput>localhost</computeroutput> on port 11211. All tables will be prefixed with <computeroutput>sp_</computeroutput> and data will expire after 3600 seconds  Caching  Memcache Caches data to memcached Registered for URLs with the &quot;memcached&quot; protocol For example, <computeroutput>memcached://localhost:11211/?timeout=3600&amp;prefix=sp_</computeroutput> will connect to memcached on <computeroutput>localhost</computeroutput> on port 11211. All tables will be prefixed with <computeroutput>sp_</computeroutput> and data will expire after 3600 seconds  Caching  Paul L. McNeely  Memcached Caches data to a MySQL database Registered for URLs with the &quot;mysql&quot; protocol For example, <computeroutput>mysql://root:password@localhost:3306/mydb?prefix=sp_</computeroutput> will connect to the <computeroutput>mydb</computeroutput> database on <computeroutput>localhost</computeroutput> on port 3306, with the user <computeroutput>root</computeroutput> and the password <computeroutput>password</computeroutput>. All tables will be prefixed with <computeroutput>sp_</computeroutput>  Caching SimplePie Redis Cache Extension  Jan Kozak <link xlink:href="mailto:galvani78@gmail.com">galvani78@gmail.com</link>  <link xlink:href="http://galvani.cz/">http://galvani.cz/</link>  <link xlink:href="http://www.opensource.org/licenses/bsd-license.php">http://www.opensource.org/licenses/bsd-license.php</link> BSD License  0.2.9 Caches data to redis Registered for URLs with the &quot;redis&quot; protocol For example, <computeroutput>redis://localhost:6379/?timeout=3600&amp;prefix=sp_&amp;dbIndex=0</computeroutput> will connect to redis on <computeroutput>localhost</computeroutput> on port 6379. All tables will be prefixed with <computeroutput>simple_primary-</computeroutput> and data will expire after 3600 seconds  Caching  Redis Handles <computeroutput>&lt;media:text&gt;</computeroutput> captions as defined in Media RSS. Used by { SimplePie_Enclosure::get_caption()} and { SimplePie_Enclosure::get_captions()} This class can be overloaded with { SimplePie::set_caption_class()}  API Manages all category-related data Used by { SimplePie_Item::get_category()} and { SimplePie_Item::get_categories()} This class can be overloaded with { SimplePie::set_category_class()}  API Content-type sniffing Based on the rules in <link xlink:href="http://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-abarth-mime-sniff-06">http://tools.ietf.org/html/draft-abarth-mime-sniff-06</link> This is used since we can&apos;t always trust Content-Type headers, and is based upon the HTML5 parsing rules. This class can be overloaded with { SimplePie::set_content_type_sniffer_class()}  HTTP Manages <computeroutput>&lt;media:copyright&gt;</computeroutput> copyright tags as defined in Media RSS Used by { SimplePie_Enclosure::get_copyright()} This class can be overloaded with { SimplePie::set_copyright_class()}  API SimplePie class. Class for backward compatibility.   deprecated 218. SimplePie} directly  API Handles <computeroutput>&lt;media:credit&gt;</computeroutput> as defined in Media RSS Used by { SimplePie_Enclosure::get_credit()} and { SimplePie_Enclosure::get_credits()} This class can be overloaded with { SimplePie::set_credit_class()}  API Decode HTML Entities This implements HTML5 as of revision 967 (2007-06-28)   deprecated 219. Handles everything related to enclosures (including Media RSS and iTunes RSS) Used by { SimplePie_Item::get_enclosure()} and { SimplePie_Item::get_enclosures()} This class can be overloaded with { SimplePie::set_enclosure_class()}  API General SimplePie exception class Used for fetching remote files and reading local files Supports HTTP 1.0 via cURL or fsockopen, with spotty HTTP 1.1 support This class can be overloaded with { SimplePie::set_file_class()}  HTTP  todo 40. Decode &apos;gzip&apos; encoded HTTP data  HTTP  <link xlink:href="http://www.gzip.org/format.txt">http://www.gzip.org/format.txt</link> HTTP Response Parser  HTTP IRI parser/serialiser/normaliser  HTTP  Sam Sneddon  Steve Minutillo  Ryan McCue  2007-2012 Sam Sneddon, Steve Minutillo, Ryan McCue  <link xlink:href="http://www.opensource.org/licenses/bsd-license.php">http://www.opensource.org/licenses/bsd-license.php</link> Manages all item-related data Used by { SimplePie::get_item()} and { SimplePie::get_items()} This class can be overloaded with { SimplePie::set_item_class()}  API Used for feed auto-discovery This class can be overloaded with { SimplePie::set_locator_class()} Miscellanous utilities Class to validate and to work with IPv6 addresses.  HTTP  2003-2005 The PHP Group  <link xlink:href="http://www.opensource.org/licenses/bsd-license.php">http://www.opensource.org/licenses/bsd-license.php</link>  <link xlink:href="http://pear.php.net/package/Net_IPv6">http://pear.php.net/package/Net_IPv6</link>  Alexander Merz <link xlink:href="mailto:alexander.merz@web.de">alexander.merz@web.de</link>  elfrink at introweb dot nl  Josh Peck &lt;jmp at joshpeck dot org&gt;  Sam Sneddon <link xlink:href="mailto:geoffers@gmail.com">geoffers@gmail.com</link> Date Parser  Parsing Parses XML into something sane This class can be overloaded with { SimplePie::set_parser_class()}  Parsing Handles <computeroutput>&lt;media:rating&gt;</computeroutput> or <computeroutput>&lt;itunes:explicit&gt;</computeroutput> tags as defined in Media RSS and iTunes RSS respectively Used by { SimplePie_Enclosure::get_rating()} and { SimplePie_Enclosure::get_ratings()} This class can be overloaded with { SimplePie::set_rating_class()}  API Handles creating objects and calling methods Access this via { SimplePie::get_registry()} Handles <computeroutput>&lt;media:restriction&gt;</computeroutput> as defined in Media RSS Used by { SimplePie_Enclosure::get_restriction()} and { SimplePie_Enclosure::get_restrictions()} This class can be overloaded with { SimplePie::set_restriction_class()}  API Used for data cleanup and post-processing This class can be overloaded with { SimplePie::set_sanitize_class()}   todo 44. Handles <computeroutput>&lt;atom:source&gt;</computeroutput> Used by { SimplePie_Item::get_source()} This class can be overloaded with { SimplePie::set_source_class()}  API Parses the XML Declaration  Parsing </link></para>
</formalpara>
</para>
</section>
</section>
